walpolea@gmail.com 541.331.3770 Andrew Walpole San Diego, CA willing to relocate



WEB DEVELOPER
EXPERIENCE DESIGNER
LEADER OF PEOPLE

# TL;DR

I'm an expert developer and designer with strengths in problem solving, strategic thinking and leading people.

I have over a decade of experience designing technical systems to meet business needs, specifically through web applications and data services.

I've led teams through organized, agile design and development processes as well as rapid prototyping for product validation.

Design is important, UX is essential, but programming is my first love. I love learning new systems and languages, creating, and solving problems through code.

I'm passionate about workplace innovation, lean methodologies, and strong company culture.

I'm looking for a challenging, purpose-driven workplace that empowers me to drive organizational success through technology, design, and experiences.



http://andrewwwalpole.com

# **EDUCATION**

**B.S. WEB DESIGN AND INTERACTIVE MEDIA** 

THE ART INSTITUTE OF CALIFORNIA - SAN DIEGO, CA - 2008

A.E. SOFTWARE ENGINEERING TECHNOLOGY

OREGON INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY - KLAMATH FALLS, OREGON - 2005

# SKILLS, STRENGTHS & CAPABILITIES

#### DEVELOPMENT

Web Application Architecture
Platform, CMS & API Integration
HTML / CSS / JavaScript / JQuery
Angular 2 / Ionic 2 / TypeScript
PHP / MySQL / NoSQL / Node.js
Git / Github / Bitbucket / SVN
Mobile App Development
Database Architecture
00P / Design Patterns
Systems Administration
Agile Development

#### DESIGN

Web Design
Graphic Design
Marketing / Branding
UX Design
Instructional Design
Prototyping
Video Production / Editing
Animation / Motion Graphics
Audio Production
Adobe Creative Cloud
3D Modeling / 3D Printing

#### LEADERSHIP

People / Talent Management
Consulting
Problem Solving
Change Management
Dealing with Ambiguity
Corporate & Team Strategy
Strategic Execution
Product Management
Project Management
Lean & Design Thinking
Teaching

## **WORK HISTORY**

SEE PAGE 2 FOR DETAILED EXPERIENCE

#### MANAGER, EXPERIENCE DESIGN / FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

JACK IN THE BOX INC. - SAN DIEGO, CA - MARCH 2009 TO PRESENT

Managed team to provide design solutions for training, communication, HR, and other corporate and brand business units. Provided capabilities such as, photography, video and audio production, graphic design, live webcasts, web design and development, web application development, UX consulting, 3D printing and more.

#### **ADJUNCT PROFESSOR**

UC SAN DIEGO EXTENSION - SAN DIEGO, CA - OCT 2014 TO PRESENT THE ART INSTITUTE OF CALIFORNIA - SAN DIEGO, CA - APRIL 2009 TO OCT 2013

Taught advanced ActionScript 3.0 programming, HTML5 & CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Mobile Programming Concepts (Cordova), and The Business of Digital Media courses.

#### WEB DESIGNER & FLASH DEVELOPER

INTERCASTING CORP. - SAN DIEGO, CA - OCT 2006 TO MARCH 2009

Designed and developed the corporate website. Assisted with graphic design needs. Built prototype phone applications with Flash and FlashLite.

#### **DATA ENTRY TECHNICIAN**

I-SAFE AMERICA INC. - SAN DIEGO, CA - SUMMER 2005

Wrote scripts to crawl websites and pull public school information into a database.

#### **ENGINEERING INTERN**

NAPSTER - SAN DIEGO, CA - SUMMER 2004

Developed Perl scripts within the music import system to resize album cover images for app use.

walpolea@gmail.com 541.331.3770 Andrew Walpole San Diego, CA willing to relocate

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Led a team of designers & developers. Focused on talent management, aligning capabilities to business, continuous skill building, efficient and agile project processes, and creating an engaging and happy work environment.

Built a new department with strategic capabilities around digital design, development, communication and culture change.

Promoted design thinking and lean startup concepts in work processes; helped move the culture toward customer/problem-focused vs. top-down/solution-focused.

Implemented consulting strategy to move from production-based team to design team focused on problem-solving and the customer experience.

Drove the "how" in departmental and corporate strategy. Defined actions and behaviors that followed the path toward accomplishing strategic goals.

Moved company training solution away from proprietary and costly LMS to distributed service architecture with in-house built components to maximize the value of custom content and react to the needs and changes in the business and industry.

Architected, product managed and developed web-based training application built on AngularJS. Integrated cloud-based CMS and analytics services.

Conducted user testing and analysis to inform continuous, iterative development or prototypes and developed applications.

Built internal services and scripts to optimize common work including: project request system, Oracle to web database sync, unconference scheduling tool, automation scripts for building flash-based training content, and weekly team engagement survey visualization page to monitor team health.

Prototyped application systems, proof of concepts, interface ideas for rapid validation.

Used 3D printing to prototype kitchen hardware including shake mixing spindle heads, burger patty temperature probe spacing-plate, and a self-serve sauce dispenser.

Managed 6-figure team budget, conducted performance reviews, set expectations and motivated team toward accomplishing clearly laid out vision and strategy.



WEB DEVELOPER
EXPERIENCE DESIGNER
LEADER OF PEOPLE

# INFLUENTIAL READING













